A classic tale of sex, revenge, and love
Edward II is a history, romance, drama film directed by Derek Jarman.
England, 14th century.
King Edward II falls in love with Piers Gaveston, a young man of humble
origins, whom he honors with favors and titles of nobility.
The cold and jealous Queen Isabella conspires with the evil Mortimer to
get rid of Gaveston, overthrow her husband and take power…
Edward II, played by Steven Waddington.
Piers Gaveston, played by Andrew Tiernan.
Isabella, played by Tilda Swinton.
Roger Mortimer, played by Nigel Terry.
Spencer, played by John Lynch.
Bishop of Winchester, played by Dudley Sutton.
Edward II is a 1991 British romantic historical drama film directed by Derek Jarman
and starring Steven Waddington, Tilda Swinton and Andrew Tiernan.
It is based on the play of the same name by Christopher Marlowe.
The plot revolves around Edward II of England's infatuation with Piers Gaveston, which proves to
be the downfall of both of them, thanks to the machinations of Roger Mortimer.
The film is staged in a postmodern style, using a mixture of
contemporary and medieval props, sets and clothing.
(The date "1991" appears on a royal proclamation at one point.) The gay content of the play is also brought to the fore by
Jarman, notably by adding a homosexual sex scene and by depicting Edward's army as gay rights protesters.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship, based on play or
musical, male homosexuality, palace intrigue, medieval england.
The tone is emotional.